Christopher K. Burns

407-45 Dunfield avenue, Toronto, Ontario, M4S2H4 | chris.burns006@gmail.com | 647-308-0344|

Github: ckzard

About

A future focused, problem solving, critical thinker from the University of Toronto with wide ranging experience and diverse skillset. Three years of experience working in the financial sector in financial services and fraud analytics. Proven track record of exceeding productivity in high pressure and demanding environments. Aptitude for taking on complex problems, finding scaleable solutions, and implementing them efficiently. Passion for data analytics, cybersecurity and threat-hunting.

Education

Honours Bachelor of Arts University of Toronto - (2012 -2016)

Degree in Political Science and History Other courses taken include Computer Science, International Law and Economics

Career Skills

- Bi-lingual (Fluent in English and French)
- Proficient in Microsoft suite (Word, Excel, PowerPoint etc.)
- Experienced in JavaScript, CSS3, HTML5, Node, Express, jQuery, Bootstrap
- Proficient in Python and C++
- Proficient in MySQL, MongoDB, SAS
- Experience in network troubleshooting

Development Experience

Spacebook - January 2021

- Developed a social media site where users can join, post Moments, add friends, check current news and weather and much more.
- The site was built using Node JS and Express, backend managed with a MySql database.
- I was responsible for all backend programming mentioned above, from creating and managing the database, authentication, routing for the page, as well as front end javascript and deploying to Heroku.
- The tool provides users an ad-free space to interact and socialize during a period with a distinct lack of world-wide socialization.
- Utilizes Node JS, Express, Passport, Bcrypt, Sequelize.
- https://spacebookx.herokuapp.com/

IDCF Auto-Tool - December 2020

• Developed a dashboard to automate data retrieval for teammates within CIBC fraud management team.

- The dashboard is a web application packaged in electron and packaged/deployed as an .exe, users
 run it locally and input key variables related to the profile they are investigating to pull key data
 for their own analysis.
- The tool increases productivity across the department by ~15%, equivalent to adding 7 new employees
- Utilizes Node JS, Bootstrap, Puppeteer, Electron among others.

Perfect Pairings - November 2020

- Managed and contributed to the development of an application that takes a user's choice for a meal and provides a perfect drink to pair.
- Responsible for coding the functionality, logic and API managment.
- Languages used include Javascript, Jquery, CSS and Bulma as well as Spoonacular API and Giphy Api.
- https://ckzard.github.io/perfectpairings/ [Username: Guest | Password: 123456]

Weather Dashboard - November 2020

- The dashboard allows users to search for a city, provide current weather, 5 day forecast and the ability to save to their favorites.
- Languages used include Javascript, Jquery, CSS and Bootstrap, as well as OpenWeather API.
- https://ckzard.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/

Professional Experience

Fraud Specialist- Compromised Account Detection (January 2021- current)

CIBC

• Developed programs and scripts to parse datasets for fraud investigations.

Consultant, Automation - Process Engineering (January 2021–current)

CIBC

- Brought on as a consultant in development of automation project for fraud managment, based on automation tool I personally developed.
- Provided insight into intricacies of profiling process to process engineering team due to my previous experience as an agent within the role.
- Designed UI for RPA automation team to implement within Blueprism process.

Fraud Analyst - <u>Impersonations and Debit Card Fraud</u> (February 2019 – January 2021) **CIBC**

- Analyzing client profiles to build a holistic view of account activity in order to identify unauthorized fraudulent activity.
- Utilization of various programs and systems to track devices and IP addresses being used to breach accounts and/or phish information from clients.
- Expert level usage of Fraud Analyst Engine in detecting fraudulent online activity and mitigating it to prevent losses.
- Recognizing current trends used by third-party fraudsters and adapting our current processes to react and prevent financial losses for our clients and CIBC.
- Developed a profiling guide for new analysts to follow in order to mitigate losses and accelerate the early learning process.

- Provided second level support to Banking Center leaders as part of pilot to prevent client impersonation in branches across Canada.
- In the process of developing applications to improve the efficiency of profiling and automating certain functions.

Financial Service Representative – <u>Inbound Loyalty Team</u> (July 2017 – February 2019) **CIBC**

- Engaged with clients to meet immediate and future needs, offer advice, handle objections and fuel financial literacy.
- Provided exceptional customer service to high-value and Imperial Service clients in order to give personalized and professional advice.
- Diligent analysis of each client in order to maintain the security and integrity of CIBC, as well as to protect our clients' information and finances.
- Evaluated client requests, and engaged other teams as needed to ensure issues were resolved in a timely manner.
- Troubleshooting Online Banking issues, E-Transfer and Global Money Transfer requests, tracking disputes in order to resolve ongoing requests while maintaining AML standards and mitigating risk to the bank.

Volunteer Experience

John Tory Electoral Campaign

- Analysis of debates between candidates and provided important insight into how our candidate could capitalize on his opponents' mistakes.
- Monitoring of social media modules to stay on top of breaking news articles in order to best prepare John for press conferences.
- Compiled all media coverage and reports each night for morning discussions.

International Student Association (InSA)

- This group was created at U of T in order to provide international students an opportunity to network and to give them a sense of belonging at our institution.
- It also exposes Canadian students to people from different cultures in order to broaden their worldview.
- We organized events to connect our members at restaurants and with presentations from guest lecturers from around the world in order to bolster an international community within U of T.